<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Miscellaneous poems upon several occasions. Written by a young lady.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 90KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 54 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B09536</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">80923160</idno>
  <idno type="VID">191925</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240869669</idno>
  
            <idno type="OCLC"> 80923160</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing M2229</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R180611</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">80923160</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B09536)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 191925)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; 1641-1700 ; 2895:29)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Miscellaneous poems upon several occasions. Written by a young lady.</title>
                  <author>E. W.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[6], 96 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printen [sic] for H. Hindmarsh, at the Golden-Ball in Cornhil,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London: :</pubPlace>
                  <date>M. DC. XC. VIII. [1698]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Dedication signed: E.W.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: tightly bound with some loss of text.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Trinity College (Dublin, Ireland) Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">English poetry --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-10 </date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03 </date>
            <label>Simon Charles </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03 </date>
            <label>Simon Charles</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:191925:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:191925:1"/>
            <p>Miscellaneous POEMS UPON SEVERAL OCCASIONS.</p>
            <p>Written by a Young <hi>Lady.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON:</hi> Printen for <hi>H. Hindmarsh,</hi> at the <hi>Golden-Ball</hi> in <hi>Cornhil.</hi> M.DC.XC.VIII.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="dedication">
            <pb facs="tcp:191925:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:191925:2"/>
            <head>TO Edw. Irby Esq;</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>SIR,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>SInce 'tis Resolv'd that my Private Thoughts must run the Gauntlet through this Censorious Age, and be Exposed as well to the Critical and Unkind, as to the Good humour'd, and the Brave, I cannot think of a more Generous and Worthy Defender then your Self. And the only good O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pinion I have of my Judgment, is in the Choice I have made of my Patron.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:191925:3"/>
            <p>To Treat you Sir, according to th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Esteem I have of your Merit, is Care<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>fully to avoid all Strain'd and Flo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>rishing Expressions in Praise of thos<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> many Excellent Virtues and Good Qua<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>lities all that have the Honour to kno<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> you find you are Master of. No, su<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> Theams tho' full of Truth and Charm<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> are far above my humble Flights, n<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> are you to be Pleased with Attempts <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> that Nature.</p>
            <p>To divert a Youthful Fancy, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Thoughtful Hour, First put me upo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> these Poetick Strains, but little thoug<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> the unhappy Product would have prov<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> a Fugitive, and given me Cause to ow<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> her with a Blush, but all these Strugglin<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> and unpolish'd Lines, were Surprize<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> from me by a Person who does design t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Print them, (if possible) more Unco<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>rect then These, which to Prevent, wa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb facs="tcp:191925:3"/> the only Motive induced me to Publish what I have not Vanity enough to be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve can Oblige so Ingenious an Age as this. But your Powerful Name fix'd in the Front, bears such a Charm, as like the Flaming Sword placed by the Tree of Life, will Shield me from the Fate I justly may deserve.</p>
            <p>I never yet Debased my Conversa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion with any thing so mean as Flat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tery, and am sure far from the Odious Vice, when I say you are Critically a Gentleman, in Honour, Birth, and E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ucation, and tho' that Generous Name <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>erves only now to shelter Inglorious Actions, yet you by Virtuous Princi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>les and Noble Practice, give new Life and Lustre, to the Dying Title; <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nder such shelter then my Poor Young Blushing Muse must hide from
<pb facs="tcp:191925:4"/> the hard Censure of the World, an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> from your Goodness hope, 'tis only that will make you Suspend your bet<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ter Judgment and Pardon the Errors of,</p>
            <closer>
               <salute>SIR,</salute>
               <signed>Your Obliged Kinswoman and Servant, E. W.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="occasional_poems">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:191925:4"/>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>TO His Majesty AT His Return from WAR, <hi>November,</hi> 1697.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>AS Eastern Worlds do to their Altars bow,</l>
                  <l>Such Reverence, Dread Sir, I pay to You;</l>
                  <l>And tho' in meanest Verse my Numbers flow,</l>
                  <l>Simplicity does true Devotion show:</l>
                  <l>The World's inspir'd with your Victorious Arm,</l>
                  <l>Which does the Hero fire and Coward warm;</l>
                  <l>And we, alas! think all our Charms too few,</l>
                  <l>And would turn <hi>Amazons</hi> to fight for you;</l>
                  <pb n="2" facs="tcp:191925:5"/>
                  <l>Throw at your feet, Great Sir, our Vanquish'd Crown,</l>
                  <l>Valour than Beauty still has more renown:</l>
                  <l>Whilst the whole World abroad in Peace we see,</l>
                  <l>And now no subject left for Victory,</l>
                  <l>Valour and Conduct shall your Motto be.</l>
                  <l>My Virgin Muse unus'd to Court address,</l>
                  <l>With all Submission does her fault Confess;</l>
                  <l>Nor dares she hope a Pardon from her King,</l>
                  <l>Presuming on so mean an Offering;</l>
                  <l>Yet humbly begs you'l mitigate her Fate,</l>
                  <l>Your Brightness did her Mind Illuminate.</l>
                  <l>Let <hi>Caesar</hi> not Condemn her bashful Lays,</l>
                  <l>Whose Glory first her insect Muse did raise:</l>
                  <l>In you I see the Charms of being Brave,</l>
                  <l>And scorn the Softness does my Sex inslave;</l>
                  <l>Did Clemency not over-rule your Power,</l>
                  <l>Could like the <hi>Macedonian</hi> King devour;</l>
                  <l>But you abhor th' insatiat thirst of Blood,</l>
                  <l>And mix your Greatness with your Subjects Good;</l>
                  <l>Whilst you with welcome Arms betimes bring home</l>
                  <l>The Wealth he won and Peace of Christendom,</l>
                  <pb n="3" facs="tcp:191925:5"/>
                  <l>Such wondrous blessings as could ne're be given</l>
                  <l>To happy <hi>Albion,</hi> but by You and Heaven.</l>
                  <l>And tho' I shared the unhappy Virgins fate,</l>
                  <l>I'd meet Thee, mighty <hi>Jeptha,</hi> at the Gate,</l>
                  <l>My life your welcome to Congratulate;</l>
                  <l>With Songs and Dances your glad Triumphs meet,</l>
                  <l>As <hi>Judah's</hi> Daughters <hi>Israel's</hi> King did greet,</l>
                  <l>And scatter Palms and Lawrels at your feet.</l>
                  <l>May Angels here your sacred Temples Guard;</l>
                  <l>And joys Eternal be your just reward;</l>
                  <l>Nor may you want the Blessings which you bring,</l>
                  <l>Till Heaven Crowns you an Immortal King.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>The Absolute.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>IF you devide your Love,</l>
                  <l>Then I must bid Adieu;</l>
                  <l>How can I ever happy prove,</l>
                  <l>When with but part of you?</l>
                  <l>Or let my Rival, or let me</l>
                  <l>Injoy your Love alone;</l>
                  <pb n="4" facs="tcp:191925:6"/>
                  <l>I Scorn a Part in any Heart,</l>
                  <l>Who has not All, has None.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>The True POET.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>HE's the only true Poet, who lives by his Wit▪</l>
                  <l>Who still veers to that Point where eac<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> humour does sit;</l>
                  <l>Who for every Meal a new Stratagem knows,</l>
                  <l>Who never speaks Truth, in Verse or in Prose;</l>
                  <l>Who Swears to that Promise he resolves not to keep▪</l>
                  <l>Whose Person and Lodging each day are to seek;</l>
                  <l>He Breakfasts with <hi>Ovid,</hi> with <hi>Epictetus</hi> does Dine,</l>
                  <l>He Drinks at <hi>Parnassus,</hi> and sups with the Nine:</l>
                  <l>By his Cloths you may know he's of Publick renown,</l>
                  <l>As an Ancient Collegean is known by his Gown;</l>
                  <l>His Pockets are stuft with Addresses to Nobles,</l>
                  <l>While Dinner rewards Panegyrical troubles,</l>
                  <l>Else Stomach is Passive and takes Non-resistance,</l>
                  <l>For Doctrin taught by the Primitive Christians,</l>
                  <pb n="5" facs="tcp:191925:6"/>
                  <l>Up Three pair of Stairs the next Door to the Sky<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>light,</l>
                  <l>You may find the Contemplative Substance at twi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>light;</l>
                  <l>But if you should stay for the light of <hi>Aurora,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>He is brush'd out abroad to Beg or to Borrow.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>On Absence.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>CAn I thy Absence any longer bear,</l>
                  <l>And to thy Memory not shed a Tear?</l>
                  <l>No, I could weep a Flood would quench the World,</l>
                  <l>Could <hi>Phaëton</hi> a second time be hurl'd</l>
                  <l>Off from his Flaming Chariot down below,</l>
                  <l>Nay, I could weep a second Deluge too:</l>
                  <l>I could turn <hi>Cynick</hi> and out rage the Wind,</l>
                  <l>Fly from all Courts from Business and Mankind;</l>
                  <l>All other Charms are empty Nothings to</l>
                  <l>Those solid comforts, I have lost in you.</l>
                  <l>Oh! Happiness! if happiness be ought,</l>
                  <l>Besides a wild Chimera of the Thought,</l>
                  <pb n="6" facs="tcp:191925:7"/>
                  <l>In your dear Company alone 'tis plac'd,</l>
                  <l>For when you're absent all things are defac'd:</l>
                  <l>When you are gone the Birds forget their Spring,</l>
                  <l>And in soft murmuring complaints they sing,</l>
                  <l>And Ants forget to bring their Harvest in.</l>
                  <l>All things neglective of their Pleasure lay,</l>
                  <l>When you their kind directer are away,</l>
                  <l>If all these kind Insensibles can grieve</l>
                  <l>What's then my Fate? or what can me relieve?</l>
                  <l>While thinking on the happy hours that past</l>
                  <l>When our united Souls were linkt so fast,</l>
                  <l>It brings fresh anguish to my tortur'd heart,</l>
                  <l>Which since I saw you has not left to smart;</l>
                  <l>For when you'r absent I must always mourn,</l>
                  <l>Who cannot hope, but wish for a Return:</l>
                  <l>If Prayers and wishes both successless prove,</l>
                  <l>I'le be both Slave and Martyr to my Love;</l>
                  <l>For when we always wish and never find,</l>
                  <l>We prove both Slaves and Martyrs to our mind.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <pb n="7" facs="tcp:191925:7"/>
               <head>On <hi>Melina</hi>'s leaving <hi>Lucinda</hi> in a Passion.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>YE Gods have ye no Quiet left in store</l>
                  <l>For wretched me, who nothing else implore;</l>
                  <l>I ask not Pleasure, Honour, Wealth or Fame,</l>
                  <l>Nor do I court the Vulgar for a Name,</l>
                  <l>A peaceful life alone can make me blest,</l>
                  <l>More than if with the World I was possest,</l>
                  <l>For which —</l>
                  <l>I chose a Partner which I thought would be</l>
                  <l>The sweet divertor of my hours and me,</l>
                  <l>For her I did refuse the charming Grove,</l>
                  <l>Made for the <hi>Cyprian</hi> Queen and God of Love;</l>
                  <l>For her I did my near Allies forsake,</l>
                  <l>For her I did a Country Life betake,</l>
                  <l>I left the glittering Glories of the Town,</l>
                  <l>And did for her their dear Allurement shun;</l>
                  <l>A lonely solitary Life I chose</l>
                  <l>For her alone in whom I'd plac'd repose.</l>
                  <pb n="8" facs="tcp:191925:8"/>
                  <l>She too with equal ardour did express,</l>
                  <l>In me alone she'd fixt her happiness;</l>
                  <l>Raptures too great for any to express,</l>
                  <l>Such as even dying Lovers confess;</l>
                  <l>Would she each day harangue away my hours</l>
                  <l>And to her witness call th' Almighty Pow'rs.</l>
                  <l>But now by some uncommon Passions mov'd</l>
                  <l>She laughs at me and slights her most Belov'd.</l>
                  <l>All that I write or say displeases now,</l>
                  <l>Nor looks on me without contracted brow;</l>
                  <l>Not all Compliance in the world will do,</l>
                  <l>Nor will she fail to cast Reflections too;</l>
                  <l>Her bar<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> surmizes is enough to prove</l>
                  <l>I'm not in humour, mad, or else in Love;</l>
                  <l>Or any thing that she but thinks must be,</l>
                  <l>Then runs divisions on her thoughts and me;</l>
                  <l>And then Again —</l>
                  <l>So kind she seems, so cordial in her way,</l>
                  <l>That o're my heart she bears an absolute sway:</l>
                  <l>And has an Art which I scarce ever knew</l>
                  <l>She at one time's both kind and cruel too.</l>
                  <pb n="9" facs="tcp:191925:8"/>
                  <l>But let her think when e're she acts that Part,</l>
                  <l>The cruel stabs the kindness in the heart,</l>
                  <l>Oh! that I could but <hi>Level</hi> once her Mind,</l>
                  <l>Not to be too severe, nor too too kind,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>'d undergo the utmost Fate can send,</l>
                  <l>Provided <hi>She</hi> were still to be my Friend:</l>
                  <l>My Life's fatigue would all a Pleasure seem</l>
                  <l>And glide apace like to a short liv'd Dream:</l>
                  <l>But 'tis too much ye Gods, I should not then</l>
                  <l>Find a Distinction from Immortal Men.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>The Disobliged.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>'TIS Vertues Dictate, and I always must</l>
                  <l>Be to my Word and to my Honour just;</l>
                  <l>To keep my Word my Honour is engag'd,</l>
                  <l>Tho' honour tells me I am disoblig'd:</l>
                  <l>My Word is Sacred, so's my Honour too,</l>
                  <l>To keep my Word my Honour I undo.</l>
                  <l>For she who does so light her Honour set,</l>
                  <l>Must loose her claim to Modesty or Wit.</l>
                  <pb n="10" facs="tcp:191925:9"/>
                  <l>Religion teaches Injuries t'receive,</l>
                  <l>On this account th' Affront I do forgive;</l>
                  <l>To keep my Word I my Resentments quit,</l>
                  <l>And as I Pardon, I'll as fast forget:</l>
                  <l>But from this Resolution ne're to swerve,</l>
                  <l>Humours by nicest caution to observe;</l>
                  <l>A modest gayety <hi>is what I'm sure</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>By Persons civiliz'd;</hi> esteem'd secure.</l>
                  <l>But I'le no more good humour ever show</l>
                  <l>'Till I this Subtle World can better know.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>CLEOMIRA TO ALONSO.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>TO thee that by degrees would lead me on</l>
                  <l>To Love, with thy insinuating tongue,</l>
                  <l>To thee I write, that once didst cause a smart,</l>
                  <l>And with such force didst fling the fiery dart,</l>
                  <pb n="11" facs="tcp:191925:9"/>
                  <l>Pointed with Words which bear a Fatal sound,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>nd does the Breast with Poys'nous rancor wound:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ou drest your Love with all the Artful guile,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>nd then assum'd a soft bewitching stile;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>anguage so sweet as none did e're afford,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>nless design'd to kill with ev'ry Word.</l>
                  <l>And what defence could my weak Breast have made,</l>
                  <l>Whom none did e're before with Charms invade;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>till when my Heart a Brisk allarm did beat,</l>
                  <l>My lovely Foe promis'd a Fair retreat,</l>
                  <l>Till Love that Bane, <hi>perfum'd t' infect</hi> the Mind,</l>
                  <l>That sad Delight that charms all Woman kind,</l>
                  <l>Transsixt my Soul and made it purely thine.</l>
                  <l>When all was done the Victory was lost,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>n gaining Conquests which you ne're can boast;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>or none will e're Applaud so mean an Act,</l>
                  <l>When Foes are poorly by surprize attackt.</l>
                  <l>By all my Flatter'd hopes 'twould ne're have done,</l>
                  <l>Unless y' had come by challenge fairly on:</l>
                  <l>Then I your Passion could have boldly heard,</l>
                  <l>And with just Answers then have been prepar'd.</l>
                  <pb n="12" facs="tcp:191925:10"/>
                  <l>And when th' Account of Love did once appear,</l>
                  <l>I could be even with you in th' arrear.</l>
                  <l>Suppose you had undone a harmless Maid,</l>
                  <l>Whose Youth had by your Folly been betray'd;</l>
                  <l>Suppose your wiles her generous heart had won,</l>
                  <l>To make Attonement, what would you have done?</l>
                  <l>To Marry her, you would have scorn'd the name,</l>
                  <l>That would have been a Scandal to your Fame;</l>
                  <l>To think the Heir o'th' Family should wed</l>
                  <l>Any that brought not Thousands with her head;</l>
                  <l>I cannot blame you neither, for I'le swear</l>
                  <l>Mony's the only thing that now is dear,</l>
                  <l>So we may call some Persons whom we like,</l>
                  <l>But nought so near the heart as Riches strike,</l>
                  <l>Yet nor your Greatness nor Estate could move</l>
                  <l>My heart, that scorns such mercenary Love,</l>
                  <l>But 'twas pure Gratitude that gave you mine,</l>
                  <l>Thinking (alas) I had some share in thine;</l>
                  <l>How could you find a Heart to ruine mine,</l>
                  <l>Mine that was always tender, soft and kind;</l>
                  <l>That never then had known what Love had meant,</l>
                  <l>Or had a Thought of which I could repent;</l>
                  <pb n="13" facs="tcp:191925:10"/>
                  <l>Could you have seen me sit all greiv'd and sad,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ighing, in Sorrows blackest livery clad:</l>
                  <l>That Face you once gave undeserving praise,</l>
                  <l>Ne're to appear but under cloudy rays;</l>
                  <l>Amaze of Thought still crowding o're my brow</l>
                  <l>My Words and Actions centring still on you,</l>
                  <l>Could you have seen all this and not have thought?</l>
                  <l>Alas! poor Maid 'twas I this trouble brought,</l>
                  <l>To think you robb'd me of Repose and Rest,</l>
                  <l>The only Good with which I was Possest,</l>
                  <l>And which I prize more than the glorious <hi>Pelf</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That Fortune gives, nay though She gave her Self,</l>
                  <l>Could I yet think you could the least Relent?</l>
                  <l>And sighing say (alas) I do Repent,</l>
                  <l>I could <hi>Platonick</hi> like still Constant prove,</l>
                  <l>And never look on you with other Love;</l>
                  <l>Could I be satisfied you this could do,</l>
                  <l>I could forgive and still Live Loving you;</l>
                  <l>And seal your Pardon with my last Adieu.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <pb n="14" facs="tcp:191925:11"/>
               <head>The Supposition.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>IF partial Death should take my Better part,</l>
                  <l>I mean my Friend, my dearest friend on Earth;</l>
                  <l>What Joy could e're inhabit in my heart,</l>
                  <l>Where every day would give new Sorrows birth:</l>
                  <l>Oh cruel Thought! Why dost thy self intrude</l>
                  <l>In forcing suppositions on my Mind,</l>
                  <l>Thine is of all Intrusions still most rude,</l>
                  <l>Because most Cruel, Fatal and Unkind.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>The Debate.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>TO be Oblig'd in what I can't Refuse</l>
                  <l>Must make Amends for what I can't Excus<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>Within the Law Necessity ne're was;</l>
                  <l>Yet for <hi>a Forma Paup'ris</hi> mine must pass,</l>
                  <l>And I no more can help my being Oblig'd,</l>
                  <l>Then I can help the Town of <hi>Mons</hi> Besieg'd:</l>
                  <pb n="15" facs="tcp:191925:11"/>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>I can help my being Ungrateful; true,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>t all Acknowledgments will never do.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ctors and Lawyers Complements ne're like,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>s mighty Gold which through the Palm does strike,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>d send such Elevations to the Heart,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> does to all the Veins a Warmth impart:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> I have Doctors own a Soul above,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>king Fee Complements from them they Love:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>y nam'd I Love, only to make up Rhime;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ndship I meant, the Love I hope's no crime,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ctors may feel a Pulse in Love sometime.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ich of the Two I am oblig'd to most,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> which in thanks I kindest must accost</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> Considering am merely lost;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>e First by sickness incapacitâde,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>gag'd the last to give me friendly aid;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> I his Patient was, on his account,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ly the Others Visits do amount;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>is makes me ne're the less Oblig'd to him,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> do me Good was purely his Design;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>e first drew Obligations for my sake,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>e last did all the Pains and Trouble take;</l>
                  <pb n="16" facs="tcp:191925:12"/>
                  <l>The first but Spoke the other he did Act,</l>
                  <l>They did the Kindness Both than by compact;</l>
                  <l>The Question is, whether or no the Last,</l>
                  <l>For me alone would the Fatigue have past;</l>
                  <l>Till this Decided is I can't tell who</l>
                  <l>I am indebted, which 'tis of the Two;</l>
                  <l>I'le ask the Last if me before he'd known,</l>
                  <l>What he in Kindness would for me have done;</l>
                  <l>Or when he saw me, if he came to serve</l>
                  <l>The Doctor only, or my Life preserve;</l>
                  <l>'Tis not convenient I this Thought retain,</l>
                  <l>Better secure in Ignorance remain;</l>
                  <l>That might extort an Answer might not suit</l>
                  <l>With Virgin Modesty to hear it out;</l>
                  <l>Not that his Answer ought to question'd be,</l>
                  <l>But in Retortion to what came from me;</l>
                  <l>I had as good since I'm ne're like to know,</l>
                  <l>With equal Gratitude my thanks bestow;</l>
                  <l>And own this Life (which they did both preserv<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>Their Interest always ready to observe,</l>
                  <l>As far as Maids with Modesty can serve:</l>
                  <pb n="17" facs="tcp:191925:12"/>
                  <l>To First and Last, to Last and First be then</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>uch thanks repaid as to Uncommon Men.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>On our Present Enjoyments.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>UNhappy Man who knows not how to prize</l>
                  <l>Present Enjoyment; but what before him flies</l>
                  <l>He chases, and pursues with eager hast,</l>
                  <l>But when o'rtaken, 'tis like Pleasures past,</l>
                  <l>And through the Blessing of Possession grow</l>
                  <l>As weary of them, as they're welcome now;</l>
                  <l>Oh wondrous Man! that boasts of Reason's Power,</l>
                  <l>Yet can't observe its Dictates for an hour.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>On Passion.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>PAssion, thou black Possessor of the Soul,</l>
                  <l>From what Foul Region didst thou take thy flight?</l>
                  <l>Avoid, thou Fiend, do not my Peace controul,</l>
                  <l>But creep in Cavernes black as darkest Night;</l>
                  <pb n="18" facs="tcp:191925:13"/>
                  <l>And as thy Pedigree came first from Hell,</l>
                  <l>There take thy residence and for ever dwell.</l>
                  <l>Whilst I sit easie with a Brow serene,</l>
                  <l>Unmov'd by any violence of Fate,</l>
                  <l>Admiring those who keep not in this meen,</l>
                  <l>And so command my Love as well as Hate.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>On my having the <hi>Small Pox.</hi>
               </head>
               <lg>
                  <l>CRuel Disease, I prithee why to me</l>
                  <l>So wondrous kind? Why this Civility?</l>
                  <l>It was a Favour I did ne'er expect,</l>
                  <l>When e'er my Stars to me did you <hi>direct;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Thou that art oft so fatal to our Sex</l>
                  <l>And dost the Fairest Faces so <hi>perplex,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>How came thy Hand so softned to my Skin?</l>
                  <l>Have I done ought that might thy Favour win?</l>
                  <l>My Pen ne'er wrote, nor Tongue thy Praises spoke,</l>
                  <l>Neglect, I see, does not thy wrath provoke;</l>
                  <l>Let me advise thee, for the future be</l>
                  <l>As kind to all the Sex, as thou'rt to me;</l>
                  <pb n="19" facs="tcp:191925:13"/>
                  <l>One single Charm but lost, we are Undone,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>hose fleeting Joys, our Lovers strait are gone:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>nd if our Reign we lose, we soon shall find</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> horrid <hi>Common-Wealth</hi> amongst Mankind.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ach Man will be a Monarch to his Will,</l>
                  <l>And think each single Glance enough to kill.</l>
                  <l>No, let's continue our Imperious Reign,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>nd when we please to Frown, a Lover's slain</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>olleys</hi> of Frowns we will to <hi>Lewis</hi> give;</l>
                  <l>But on our Armies smile to make them live;</l>
                  <l>Then with our Warlike Heroes we may vie,</l>
                  <l>They Conquer by the Sword, we by the Eye:</l>
                  <l>Therefore when-e'er our softer Skins you <hi>trace,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Have mercy on the Beauties of the Face;</l>
                  <l>But on Mankind thy rugged Footsteps set</l>
                  <l>We Women like not Men Effeminate,</l>
                  <l>And you, Disease, can't hurt the Men of Wit.</l>
                  <l>And now I thank you, dear Disease, for all</l>
                  <l>Those Marks of Favour, and I ever shall,</l>
                  <l>Since you have been so very much my Friend,</l>
                  <l>Be your most humble Servant to command.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem__epithalamium">
               <pb n="20" facs="tcp:191925:14"/>
               <head>An EPITHALAMIUM ON Lady <hi>MARY OBRION.</hi>
               </head>
               <lg>
                  <l>AWake ye Mortals, be not lost</l>
                  <l>In Amorous Dreams, or restless Slumbe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> tost,</l>
                  <l>But all attend on this Victorious Pair,</l>
                  <l>In smiling Triumph to the Temple lead,</l>
                  <l>Let no forsaken Virgin now appear,</l>
                  <l>But Lovers leave their murmuring Sighs,</l>
                  <l>And clear up their despairing Eyes,</l>
                  <l>Each one may like this Happy-Brave succeed</l>
                  <l>With his assiduons care,</l>
                  <l>Mean time, each strive to Celebrate,</l>
                  <l>And sing these Happy Lovers Fate.</l>
                  <pb n="21" facs="tcp:191925:14"/>
                  <l>An Universal Good by Heav'n design'd</l>
                  <l>To match the Living-Beauties of the Mind,</l>
                  <l>And multiply new Blessings on Mankind.</l>
                  <l>Joy to the Bright <hi>Eugenia</hi>'s choice;</l>
                  <l>Let always Pleasures on her wait;</l>
                  <l>May soft <hi>Courtillo</hi>'s charming Voice,</l>
                  <l>Be all the Matrimonial Noise</l>
                  <l>Her gentler Ear shall <hi>grate;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And if there be no Wedlock without strife,</l>
                  <l>Let Love the sweet Contention be,</l>
                  <l>And to compleat their Happy Life,</l>
                  <l>May they their Image in their Off-spring see.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>On the Worthy Doctor <hi>H . . . .</hi>
               </head>
               <lg>
                  <l>PErmit me, Sir, among a thousand more</l>
                  <l>That do the Name of mighty <hi>H.</hi> adore,</l>
                  <l>To bring my humble Muse within your view,</l>
                  <l>And pay the Tribute to your Merit due.</l>
                  <l>Tis not in hopes my own applause to raise,</l>
                  <l>Who seek no other Glory than your Praise;</l>
                  <pb n="22" facs="tcp:191925:15"/>
                  <l>
                     <hi>For 'tis not flights of Wit your Worth can prize,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Too weak Efforts,</hi> by which your Name must rise,</l>
                  <l>Your Self can best your Self immortallize.</l>
                  <l>No elevated Thought of Pregnant Brain,</l>
                  <l>(Unless by Gods inspir'd) can e'er maintain,</l>
                  <l>Fit Numbers to repeat your growing Fame.</l>
                  <l>These forward <hi>Droppings</hi> you must pardon then,</l>
                  <l>The zealous Error of my Untaught Pen;</l>
                  <l>And give me leave to vent some Thoughts abroad,</l>
                  <l>Which over-run each other in the Crowd;</l>
                  <l>You'l suffer here as Hero's at their Death,</l>
                  <l>Whose Glory's lessen'd by too common Breath;</l>
                  <l>And yet each busie Fool in Rustick Sense,</l>
                  <l>Shews admiration in Impertinence.</l>
                  <l>If you so Strong our brittle Frame cement,</l>
                  <l>As not to turn to its First <note n="*" place="margin">Who Pr<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>served an <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>natomy wi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap> the Flesh.</note> Element,</l>
                  <l>And by your wondrous Art the Body save</l>
                  <l>From the cold Bosom of the gaping Grave.</l>
                  <l>All sure must wish whene'er their Pulses cease,</l>
                  <l>Your Hands may hush them to Eternal Peace;</l>
                  <l>And if the Dead you can Preserve so well,</l>
                  <l>What wonders may the Living of you tell?</l>
                  <pb n="23" facs="tcp:191925:15"/>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> by Experience Summon'd to <hi>Reveal</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Your generous Favours with Profoundest Skill:</l>
                  <l>Must own that Health which the kind Gods have given,</l>
                  <l>Below, the only antipast of Heaven;</l>
                  <l>That bounteous Blessing they did once afford</l>
                  <l>You their great Agent have again restor'd,</l>
                  <l>For which may all the Blessings that Descend</l>
                  <l>On happy Mortals, still on you attend;</l>
                  <l>In all your Mighty undertakings may</l>
                  <l>Success still wait on each Important day;</l>
                  <l>May you in all your wisht Amours succeed,</l>
                  <l>And if there be one Nimph for which you Bleed,</l>
                  <l>(If you in all the Sex can find you Fair,</l>
                  <l>That may deserve your Wishes or your Care)</l>
                  <l>May she with Charming Modesty be kind,</l>
                  <l>And Virtue be the Dowry of her Mind;</l>
                  <l>May Beauty, Youth, and Humour, all agree,</l>
                  <l>And Wit make up the pleasing Harmony;</l>
                  <l>May all these Charms still court each softer Hour,</l>
                  <l>Whene'er the God descends to shew his pow'r;</l>
                  <l>May you with Joys substantial still be Crown'd,</l>
                  <l>And be as Happy as you are Renown'd.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem__elegy">
               <pb n="24" facs="tcp:191925:16"/>
               <head>AN ELEGY On Mr. <hi>J. S.</hi> Musick-Man at the Act at <hi>Oxford,</hi> 169<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> who was reported to be killed by Hig<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>Way-men.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>OH dismal Day! Black as the Indian dye,</l>
                  <l>'Twas juster Fate decreed it, or else I</l>
                  <l>Should curse the Hour that brought it to my Eye.</l>
                  <l>For gone's that bravely Bold and Vent'rous Youth,</l>
                  <l>Who in this Age ev'n dar'd to speak the Truth;</l>
                  <l>And not long since in <hi>Rostrum</hi> brought to light,</l>
                  <l>The deeds of many done in darkest night.</l>
                  <l>'Tis he whose strength of Words did batter down,</l>
                  <l>Vices of either Petticoat or Gown,</l>
                  <l>From Weakest to best Fortify'd in Town.</l>
                  <pb n="25" facs="tcp:191925:16"/>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> Lovely Youth! <hi>Oxford</hi> must be to you</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>bted still for Virtues that ensue,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ose Theatre St. <hi>Mary</hi>'s can out-do.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>sure must mourn at thy Untimely Fate,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>rime of Years pluckt from a good Estate;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> going to reap the Fruit his Father sow'd,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>th Cropt him with the Scyth he should have mow'd.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> poor Man! the <hi>Kentish</hi> Ladies cry,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>e <hi>Irish</hi>-Teagues o're his Dead Body sigh,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>e does the Hope of many a Virgin lie.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>andsome Proper Man, and Brave Estate,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> cruel Highway-men! Oh barbarous Fate!</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> since he's gone, and Sorrow can't retrieve</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> fleeting Soul, why should we longer Grieve?</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> let us by a Nobler method try,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> make his Name live to Eternity;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> at were a Subject would ev'n <hi>Creech</hi> provoke,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> Grief did not his lofty Fancy choke:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> we're my weaker Pen must give it o'er,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ho only can this suddain Loss deplore,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>d pray that Heav'n afflict us so no more.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <pb n="26" facs="tcp:191925:17"/>
               <head>THE PROPHESIE</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>FAte has a Leaf of her large Book turn'd o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>A Leaf which I ne'er read but once before▪</l>
                  <l>And yet a Leaf I fain would read once more.</l>
                  <l>When first I look'd on this Mysterious side,</l>
                  <l>Which treated of how Hearts to Hearts were ty'<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>Within a short Parenthesis I read,</l>
                  <l>To Whom and When <hi>Melinda</hi> was to Wed:</l>
                  <l>Very well pleas'd at her good Fortune, I</l>
                  <l>A little farther cast my wand'ring Eye;</l>
                  <l>To see, if in that side it did not show</l>
                  <l>If Marriages e'er by Succession go;</l>
                  <l>If so, then next <hi>Idumia</hi> Hymen sings,</l>
                  <l>But Fate clapt up her Book, and ty'd the Strings▪</l>
                  <l>And did for this Inquisitive Offence,</l>
                  <l>Bind me Apprentice to sev'n Years suspence;</l>
                  <pb n="27" facs="tcp:191925:17"/>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>hat expir'd, she out her Folio brought,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> believ'd to satisfie each Thought;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ch did like Ladies Common-Pray'r-Books, all</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>lace of Matrimony open fall:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>e next Paragraph she let me know,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> Marriage did not by Succession go;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>hose who best could Love, and without Strife,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>d be content to make Intrigue for Life;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <hi>Astragon</hi> was next in Register,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>appy Union too it did aver:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> less pleas'd than at the time before,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>g'd she would let me look a little low'r;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> she refus'd and shut her Book up vext,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> only answer'd, I should not be next;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> live a Virgin sev'n Years longer yet,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>en wed a Man of Money, and no Wit.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ust confess, the Answer did surprize,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>d startle all m'interiour Faculties;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>d must I then an Aged Maiden grow?</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>hich in this Age is so reproachful too;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>d for a Fool to wait, I could dispence</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>he Patriarch's time, wer't for a Man of Sense.</l>
                  <pb n="28" facs="tcp:191925:18"/>
                  <l>To seize the Jilt I scarcely could forbear,</l>
                  <l>Or this curs'd Leaf out of her Book to tear;</l>
                  <l>But that I found some Justice on her side,</l>
                  <l>When Fool I thought on, thus I strait reply'd,</l>
                  <l>A Fool indeed, whoe'er makes me his Bride;</l>
                  <l>He by his choice soon to the World will show,</l>
                  <l>Whether he be'nt a Fool in grain or no:</l>
                  <l>But while black Passion did my Thoughts engage,</l>
                  <l>Fate smil'd at my Unprofitable rage,</l>
                  <l>And with a scornful Jeering sort of Scoff,</l>
                  <l>Took up her dark Decrees and so march'd off.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem__song">
               <pb n="29" facs="tcp:191925:18"/>
               <head>A <hi>SONG.</hi>
               </head>
               <lg n="1">
                  <head>I.</head>
                  <l>FOrbear fair Nymph a while to Scorn</l>
                  <l>Injoy your Youth and Love,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>'re think those Beauties with you born</l>
                  <l>Will Everlasting prove.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="2">
                  <head>II.</head>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>me passes swiftly by your Eye,</l>
                  <l>And Day each Day does chace,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>d tho'unseen to you they Fly:</l>
                  <l>I see it in your Face.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="3">
                  <head>III.</head>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>hink what your Slights to me have done:</l>
                  <l>Think e're your Beauty's past,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>hink how those Years, that o'er you run,</l>
                  <l>Will leave some Track at Last.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="30" facs="tcp:191925:19"/>
               <lg n="4">
                  <head>IV.</head>
                  <l>And when old Age and Wrinkles come,</l>
                  <l>True Antidote to Love,</l>
                  <l>Remember <hi>Cloë</hi> what you've done</l>
                  <l>And from Mankind remove.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>An Answer to a <hi>SONG</hi>
               </head>
               <lg n="1">
                  <head>I.</head>
                  <l>'TIs a Silly mistake</l>
                  <l>That Riches can Speak;</l>
                  <l>Or e're for good Rhetorick pass;</l>
                  <l>To a Fool I confess</l>
                  <l>Your Gold may address,</l>
                  <l>Where the Master's an absolute Ass.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="2">
                  <head>II.</head>
                  <l>But to Women of Sense,</l>
                  <l>'Tis a Sordid pretence:</l>
                  <l>That a Golden Effigies can move Her;</l>
                  <l>No Face on the Coin</l>
                  <l>Can be half so Divine,</l>
                  <l>As that of a Faithful young Lover.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="31" facs="tcp:191925:19"/>
               <lg n="3">
                  <head>III.</head>
                  <l>But Men when they Love</l>
                  <l>Their Passion to prove,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>om the Court, to the Dull Country Novice;</l>
                  <l>To the Fair they're so kind,</l>
                  <l>First to Fathom her mind,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ext search the Prerogative Office.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg n="4">
                  <head>IV.</head>
                  <l>No <hi>Imprimis</hi> I give,</l>
                  <l>Then the Fair one they leave,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>otwithstanding the Strong Protestation;</l>
                  <l>Till the Lady discovers</l>
                  <l>No Fortune, no Lovers,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>nd draws off Her fond Inclination.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <pb n="32" facs="tcp:191925:20"/>
               <head>On Mr. <hi>Finger's</hi> Musick in <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <hi>Anatomist,</hi> or <hi>Sham-Doctor</hi>
               </head>
               <lg>
                  <l>SIlence Ye meaner Spirits of the Air,</l>
                  <l>The Gods themselves do give attention▪</l>
                  <l>And with new pleasure cease the Spheres above,</l>
                  <l>And wonder at our harmony of Love:</l>
                  <l>Our Second <hi>Orpheus</hi> does the First excel,</l>
                  <l>This Charms the Heavens, no scornful Maid in</l>
                  <l>His Consort's too Divine for Stone or Wood,</l>
                  <l>And by the Gods alone is Understood;</l>
                  <l>In vain are all Poetick Flights to show</l>
                  <l>The Mighty Raptures which we find Below.</l>
                  <l>Transported from my Self, I'd quit each Sen<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>If in exchange I Hearing could Commence;</l>
                  <l>And when my Soul Returns I fall to Rhimes,</l>
                  <l>And Bless the happy <hi>Orpheus</hi> of our Times.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <pb n="33" facs="tcp:191925:20"/>
               <head>On a <hi>Steel Pen</hi> with a <hi>Cupid</hi> Engraven on the Top.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>GO tell Young <hi>Damon</hi> he has <hi>nibb'd</hi> my Pen</l>
                  <l>So soft, that it must never write to Men;</l>
                  <l>And tho' the Error was too harsh before,</l>
                  <l>To Err in Softness needs must make it more,</l>
                  <l>When <hi>Coridon</hi> first gave this pointed Steel,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> could not Love, that mighty Fault reveal,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ut well Instructed by the Hand that gave,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ike him it taught the Vertue to be Brave;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ut as the Finest things do first decay,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> heedless Swain soon stole the Gift away,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>nd on't impris'd a <hi>Cupid Cap a pee,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ounding a Heart, the very Heart of me;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>atal Resemblance! Since it did forebode</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> real mischief from the Angry God;</l>
                  <pb n="32" facs="tcp:191925:21"/>
                  <gap reason="duplicate" resp="#oxf" extent="1 page">
                     <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb n="33" facs="tcp:191925:21"/>
                  <gap reason="duplicate" resp="#oxf" extent="1 page">
                     <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb n="34" facs="tcp:191925:22"/>
                  <l>He need not fly through Woods and Groves to me,</l>
                  <l>Nor shoot so oft, one was as well as three,</l>
                  <l>Where Eyes can wound there needs no Deity.</l>
                  <l>'Tis strange, the Mettal of my Pen's the same</l>
                  <l>With that which Love does all his Arrows frame,</l>
                  <l>But still this mighty Difference remains,</l>
                  <l>That gives the Wound, when mine will ease the pain<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>In <hi>Vulcan</hi>'s Forge much hardness they require,</l>
                  <l>My Pen is softned by a Gentler fire;</l>
                  <l>Beat out by cruel <hi>Cyclops</hi> are his Darts,</l>
                  <l>Mine by a Softer hand and tender Art,</l>
                  <l>To tell the Grief, when t'other gives the Smart.</l>
                  <l>Blame not my Vertue when I write of Love,</l>
                  <l>Since by the God himself my fingers move.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>The Early Amour.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>I'VE Lost much time in Mirth and light Discourse▪</l>
                  <l>And spent much breath on Lovers and Love<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> force▪</l>
                  <l>My heart at Fourteen beat up Loves allarms,</l>
                  <l>And I poor Innocence set up for Charms:</l>
                  <pb n="35" facs="tcp:191925:22"/>
                  <l>E're scarce Fifteen to Courtship I gave Ear,</l>
                  <l>Heard all those things which Faithless men will Swear,</l>
                  <l>What I would have I easily believ'd,</l>
                  <l>And with my own consent too oft Deceiv'd;</l>
                  <l>I knew those Graces did not in me grow,</l>
                  <l>Yet thought 'twas fine that they should tell me so,</l>
                  <l>And did believe their Heart and Tongue enclin'd,</l>
                  <l>To prove it was no Fiction, Love was Blind.</l>
                  <l>At Sixteen years I grew extreamly Coy,</l>
                  <l>And what a Lover ask'd sure to deny;</l>
                  <l>When in my Praise their stock of Wit they spent,</l>
                  <l>And in full <hi>Gales</hi> of Sighs their Passion vent,</l>
                  <l>I seem'd all Ignorant of what they meant.</l>
                  <l>If e're by stealth they have my Fingers prest,</l>
                  <l>I learn'd my very Fingers to resist;</l>
                  <l>Thus I ran on nor stopt my full career,</l>
                  <l>Till looking back at Twenty smiling Year,</l>
                  <l>At once I found my Error, their Deceit,</l>
                  <l>Their false Insinuations, and my Fate;</l>
                  <l>But now so hardned am to all their crys,</l>
                  <l>Their far fetcht Flights, feign'd Tears and Amorous sighs,</l>
                  <pb n="36" facs="tcp:191925:23"/>
                  <l>That all the ways found out by subtil Man,</l>
                  <l>Could never make me Credit them again:</l>
                  <l>Thus did I spend my Gayity and Youth,</l>
                  <l>And found in none but <hi>Strephon</hi> Love and Truth;</l>
                  <l>For he such Faith and Constancy has shown,</l>
                  <l>As would for all the Sexes Crimes attone.</l>
                  <l>And now as free as Mountain Air I move,</l>
                  <l>My mind not <hi>Sully'd</hi> with the thoughts of Love;</l>
                  <l>And tho' my Ears too Credulous have been,</l>
                  <l>My Heart was always Innocent within;</l>
                  <l>And as it hitherto has been my Guard,</l>
                  <l>Prudence shall now assist to keep the Ward:</l>
                  <l>Thus my Lifes Scene I'le happily compleat,</l>
                  <l>Learn how to hold my Tongue and be Discreet.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>
                  <hi>Antonio</hi> to <hi>Lucinda</hi> after a P<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>sent of her Hair.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>RIch Diadems let haughty Monarchs wear,</l>
                  <l>I'm prouder in <hi>Lucinda</hi>'s brighter Hair;</l>
                  <pb n="37" facs="tcp:191925:23"/>
                  <l>Their thoughtful brows let that vile Mettal bind,</l>
                  <l>That of all ill's the Fruitful cause we find:</l>
                  <l>More pretious Wealth does round my Temples play,</l>
                  <l>Which <hi>Phoebus</hi> would prefer to <hi>Daphne's</hi> Bay.</l>
                  <l>Not Eastern Groves such fragrant Odours yield,</l>
                  <l>When wanton <hi>Zeph'rus</hi> fans the Spicy Field;</l>
                  <l>Nor does the Sun that endless Spring of light,</l>
                  <l>Shed threads of Gold so tender, and so bright,</l>
                  <l>So wondrous fine, so Charming to the sight.</l>
                  <l>Princes may boast of Fleets with Treasures fraught,</l>
                  <l>And Ill-got Wealth from distant Nations brought;</l>
                  <l>More happy I (with Reverence be it said)</l>
                  <l>To whom the Fairest Nymph our Isle e're bred,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Lucinda,</hi> pays the Tribute of her Head.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>The Hypocrite.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>TO him that Slights me I Incline,</l>
                  <l>And you that Love me shun,</l>
                  <l>Compell'd by Fate, no fault of mine,</l>
                  <l>I to my Ruine run.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="38" facs="tcp:191925:24"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>Could I unruly Fancy guide,</l>
                  <l>My thoughts you would not blame,</l>
                  <l>Rewarding you should be my Pride,</l>
                  <l>As Loving him my Shame.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then do not blame a Nymph, that grieves</l>
                  <l>Your Merit can't prevail,</l>
                  <l>Till time and chance our hopes relieves,</l>
                  <l>Your care and mine is vain.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>ON LUCINDA's Going to the <hi>Indies</hi> to be Married.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>WELL since 'tis so, come hither all, oh come,</l>
                  <l>And with me read, as if it were your doom;</l>
                  <l>For gone's <hi>Lucinda,</hi> with her all is gone,</l>
                  <l>That Vertue, or that Goodness e're put on,</l>
                  <l>Then gone's my Light, gone is my all, my Sun,</l>
                  <l>My life's extinguisht e're it was begun;</l>
                  <pb n="39" facs="tcp:191925:24"/>
                  <l>Sun, Moon and Stars if they together joyn,</l>
                  <l>Are all dull Meteors when compar'd to mine:</l>
                  <l>And without her, what e're they here call bright,</l>
                  <l>Shines but enough to shew me it is night;</l>
                  <l>But oh She's gone! alas for ever gone</l>
                  <l>And left me grov'ling in the Dark alone.</l>
                  <l>But stay Ye Gods! I at a Distance see</l>
                  <l>A glimpse of light, by Heav'ns it must be She!</l>
                  <l>Then level all; Hills into Vales remove</l>
                  <l>'Tis Love that drives, and all must yield to Love.</l>
                  <l>'Tis She, but oh! what mean these mighty Fears?</l>
                  <l>She in a Ship? the Kingdom all in Tears?</l>
                  <l>As quick as thought I thro' the World will range,</l>
                  <l>To know the Meaning of this mighty Change:</l>
                  <l>O wretched Isle with me this Loss bemoan,</l>
                  <l>The only Jewel in the Crown is gone;</l>
                  <l>She from the Center flung her Rays about,</l>
                  <l>But now She's gone they are for ever out.</l>
                  <l>But stay let's think, where can this Light be gone?</l>
                  <l>Perhaps to <hi>Greenland,</hi> there's but little Sun;</l>
                  <l>Or else yet farther, where the <hi>Serpents rowl,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Under the <hi>Center</hi> of the freezing <hi>Pole.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="40" facs="tcp:191925:25"/>
                  <l>No, no, She's gone to help, at last l've guest,</l>
                  <l>The <hi>Aged</hi> Sun in his arising East,</l>
                  <l>And there to make a Matrimonial Feast.</l>
                  <l>For since he's old, 'tis fit we there should place,</l>
                  <l>And get a Son for to maintain the Race;</l>
                  <l>Well may the <hi>Indies</hi> now of Treasure boast,</l>
                  <l>For in short time 'twill all Land on their Coast.</l>
                  <l>O Alteration! O what Change I find!</l>
                  <l>Since She is gone, if I must stay behind.</l>
                  <l>I whilst with her did all their <hi>Pelf</hi> despise,</l>
                  <l>But for the Future will their Treasure prize,</l>
                  <l>And to her Shrine offer up Sacrifice.</l>
                  <l>And this to Heav'n shall be my fervent Pray'r,</l>
                  <l>That over her it have peculiar Care:</l>
                  <l>And thou great <hi>Neptune</hi> of the mighty Deep,</l>
                  <l>Her Ship from Storms and Rocks in safety keep;</l>
                  <l>Call all your Sea Nymphs, let your Syrens see,</l>
                  <l>That on her Bark, they all <hi>Attentive</hi> be.</l>
                  <l>When on the Waves tempestuous Storms <hi>there are,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And <hi>Sol</hi> can't lend one Beam to guild the Air,</l>
                  <l>Set o're her Ship a Sky serene and clear.</l>
                  <pb n="41" facs="tcp:191925:25"/>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>en let your Dolphins all their Musick bring,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>d as she fails, glide gently by and <hi>sing.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>r ne'er till now the Ocean ever bore,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>Great, so Good, so rich a Prize before;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> wou'd have done, but oh! I can't forbear,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>r great's your Charge, and great must be your Care:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>herefore great God of all the Foaming Main,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>aft her o're Safe, Safe bring her back again.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>On the Death of My Little Niece.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>MIrror of Innocence whither art thou fled?</l>
                  <l>Above the Clouds, or dwell'st among the Dead?</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>o; thy sweet Soul's too Innocent and Bright,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>'inhabit those Eternal Shades of Night.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>eav'n is thy blest Abode, where thou dost reign</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ith thy Creator, and that numerous train</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>f glorious Saints and Angels, that do sing</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ternal Hallelujahs to their King.</l>
                  <pb n="42" facs="tcp:191925:26"/>
                  <l>While my unhappy Soul is still confin'd</l>
                  <l>To Sorrow, Sickness, and a Troubled Mind;</l>
                  <l>A Pris'ner kept within its House of Clay,</l>
                  <l>And with Impatience waits that Happy Day,</l>
                  <l>When my All-wise Creator thus shall say;</l>
                  <l>Leave thou thy dismal Mansion I thee gave,</l>
                  <l>Which shall thy better part no more enslave,</l>
                  <l>But as a Prey shall serve to treat the Grave:</l>
                  <l>Whilst thy Diviner part to me shall fly,</l>
                  <l>Where Tears shall be a Stranger to thine Eye;</l>
                  <l>For all that thou didst suffer whilst beneath,</l>
                  <l>Was only to obtain this Glorious Wreath,</l>
                  <l>I, as a Trophee of my Mercy give.</l>
                  <l>Then, Then my Airy Soul shall mount aloft,</l>
                  <l>Too fast for swiftest Time, or nimble Thought</l>
                  <l>To trace the Path, from whence it took its flight▪</l>
                  <l>So of its duller Earth it bids good Night;</l>
                  <l>When thus with fullest Joy my Soul's possest,</l>
                  <l>And with my glorious Maker's presence blest,</l>
                  <l>My Soul will then enjoy an Everlasting Rest.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <pb n="43" facs="tcp:191925:26"/>
               <head>On Secret Love.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>LIke Secret Love no Pleasure sure is known,</l>
                  <l>When Hearts become <hi>an Ʋndivided one;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>imes a Silent Joy o'er-spreads our breast,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>m delight does all our Mind invest:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> clouds of Jelousie do interpose,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <hi>Saddens</hi> all our blest and dear Repose.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> cautious Eye still with our Thought is bent,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>hes the Look which to another's sent;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>n every word bears an unusual sound,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> does our Breast with jealous horror wound;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> when these Lovers meet and Charm the Ill,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> did their Mind with <hi>Perturbation</hi> fill;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ainging Souls with new repeated Vows,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>lemn Joy mounts o'er their clouded Brows:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>y catch the coming Joy, and grasp the Prize,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>t flys with transport from each others Eyes;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>s which truths declare what Tongues conceal,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ose swifter motion all their Thoughts reveal.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <pb n="44" facs="tcp:191925:27"/>
               <head>The Conquest.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>MAN I defie, if Hostile he appears,</l>
                  <l>But dread him when he comes with <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> and Tears.</l>
                  <l>The first arms me with Pride and Insolence,</l>
                  <l>And puts me in a Posture of Defence:</l>
                  <l>The last all Rage and Anger does remove;</l>
                  <l>And only Pity leaves to aid my Love;</l>
                  <l>To see a Man of Courage, Grace, and Wit,</l>
                  <l>Poorly to weak Womanish Tears submit;</l>
                  <l>Who fears no Wars, nor does a Combat shun,</l>
                  <l>Yet, by Dear Charming Woman is undone:</l>
                  <l>See at her Feet the Charming Suppliant lies,</l>
                  <l>Whose throbbing Heart sends moisture to his E<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>There in Pathetick sounds his Love repeats,</l>
                  <l>And harden'd Virtue with beseeching Cheats.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <pb n="45" facs="tcp:191925:27"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>Lucinda</hi> to her Heart.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>UNgenerous Heart! cou'dst thou no pity have</l>
                  <l>Upon thy most Obsequious humble Slave;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>e that Ador'd and Lov'd thee with such Zeal,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ilst harden'd thou did'st no Compassion feel;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ou that could'st Laugh at all Loves Fooleries,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>d took sound Truth for Perjury and Lyes.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>e Sex you did Contemn, nor wou'd believe</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>e honest Demonstrations he did give:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>w thou art met with, Heart, and Fitted too,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ith one that can thy wondrous Pow'r out-do.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>d art thou then resolv'd to fix on one?</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>at Loves this Minute and the next is gone;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>t 'tis no Matter; you but Justice have,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ul' find but such returns as once you gave.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>u scorn'd your Lover when He talkt of Flame</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> Now you are come I fear to write the same;</l>
                  <pb n="46" facs="tcp:191925:28"/>
                  <l>When he e're sad or Melancholly was,</l>
                  <l>Ridiculous, you'd cry; what means the Ass!</l>
                  <l>Sure he do'nt think that Posture e're can cha<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>Such solid Coxcombs ne're can do me harm.</l>
                  <l>A spritely Air, an Elevated Wit</l>
                  <l>He must assume, e're I can think it fit</l>
                  <l>This Free-born Soul so humbly to Submit.</l>
                  <l>Fut when this form he took, as men you see,</l>
                  <l>Can <hi>Proteous</hi> like soon Metamorphos'd be;</l>
                  <l>Methought he look'd as if he dar'd his Fate,</l>
                  <l>And did presumptiously incur my hate:</l>
                  <l>Thus with contempt I did Mankind defie,</l>
                  <l>And brav'd those Dangers which are now too <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>Alas poor Women! thou art ne're Secure,</l>
                  <l>But must Assaults and Batteries endure</l>
                  <l>Of Charming Words, which thrown against thy B<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>The Invader Love soon Plunders all thy rest.</l>
                  <l>Did I encourage <hi>Strephon</hi> e're to say?</l>
                  <l>Ten Thousand things which did my heart betra<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>His fluent Tongue a Prompter did not want,</l>
                  <l>That cou'd ask faster much than I could Grant;</l>
                  <pb n="47" facs="tcp:191925:28"/>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> Tongue, his Eyes, each motion Spoke his Love</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> me, who did the Fatal Object prove;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ou'd I had rather been that of his hate,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>en I for ever had been Fortunate:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>here Fortunes disagree, and kindness shown,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>here hearts become an undivided One,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> suffer Separation then must be</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>e worst of Ills, that Fate can put on me.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ell —</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> that a Heart so fixt as mine can move,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> that my niggard Fortune starves my Love.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>On a Smile from <hi>Silvia.</hi>
               </head>
               <lg>
                  <l>LEt th' Ambitious proud with Courtly Toil,</l>
                  <l>Pismire like creep on their Golden Soil:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>t the Bold Merchant bring the <hi>Indies</hi> home,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>d Pave his way with Pearls and Pretious Stone;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>t <hi>Heroes</hi> to with Warlike heat inspir'd,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ght till their Arm has their whole body tir'd:</l>
                  <pb n="48" facs="tcp:191925:29"/>
                  <l>Whilst I more High, more Rich, more Laurels g<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>When I one Smile from <hi>Silvia</hi> can obtain.</l>
                  <l>For such a Favour I an Age cou'd wait,</l>
                  <l>Tho' from that hour my ruine took its date.</l>
                  <l>If e're I am Ambitiously inclin'd,</l>
                  <l>It must a Smile in <hi>Silvia's</hi> Face to find,</l>
                  <l>Pride consequently then must seize my mind.</l>
                  <l>A Merchant sure with such a Treasure stor'd,</l>
                  <l>Wou'd be more worth than <hi>Indies</hi> can afford;</l>
                  <l>How gladly wou'd I tug the lab'ring oar,</l>
                  <l>To bring such Jewels to our English shore?</l>
                  <l>Bold and Heroick too I'de fight the Prize,</l>
                  <l>For the half shut of <hi>Silvia's</hi> Mouth and Eyes:</l>
                  <l>Proud with the Conquest I'de up Laurels root,</l>
                  <l>And in them wreathed be from Head to Foot.</l>
                  <l>For this —</l>
                  <l>A King might leave His Throne with good preten<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>And yet not lessen his Magnificence.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem__song">
               <pb n="49" facs="tcp:191925:29"/>
               <head>A <hi>SONG.</hi>
               </head>
               <lg>
                  <l>AH Cruel Nymph Resign resign</l>
                  <l>That Stony Adamantine Heart,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>nd give it in exchange for Mine,</l>
                  <l>Mine that is Soft in every Part;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>or You alas have wondrous Skill,</l>
                  <l>And can more than Magicians do,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>or with your Eyes you Wound and Kill,</l>
                  <l>And Syren like you Charm me too.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ut how can I attempt that Breast?</l>
                  <l>Warm'd with Seraphick Fire,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>hat with Divinity's Possest,</l>
                  <l>And Heavenly thoughts inspire;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>may as well the Winds Pursue,</l>
                  <l>When they their Breezes on me cast,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>atch 'em and think they are my due,</l>
                  <l>When they alas are but a Blast.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <pb n="50" facs="tcp:191925:30"/>
               <head>On Friendship.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>FRiendship! that Sound does all my Senses Cha<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>And does my Soul with generous Pass<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> wa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>That Name of Friend a pleasing Accent bears,</l>
                  <l>And Crowns my Life, and Conquers all my Fears▪</l>
                  <l>For if there be a Happiness on Earth?</l>
                  <l>'Tis to a Friend, to give our Sorrows Birth.</l>
                  <l>A Friends a Cordial when our Spirits sink,</l>
                  <l>Which saves our Bodies on the tott'ring brink,</l>
                  <l>Who leaves no Thought unroul'd in his great Mi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>Nor to the Limit of a Sum's confin'd.</l>
                  <l>These are the Marks of Friendship, and were I</l>
                  <l>Either to have no Friend, or else to Die,</l>
                  <l>I'd quit the World and Generously loose</l>
                  <l>That Life that must a Dearer Friend refuse.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <pb n="51" facs="tcp:191925:30"/>
               <head>THE RESOLUTION.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>ALas! how soon are Maids undone?</l>
                  <l>When Men their Love impart,</l>
                  <l>Charming Musick of their Tongue,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>es many a Virgins Heart.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> sad Experience this I know,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>en <hi>Strephon</hi> first did Love,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> what soft tender things he'd Vow,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> to Compassion move.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> sit and Gaze out all his hours,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> Sigh out all his Words;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> Swear by the Almighty Pow'rs,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> all that Heav'n affords.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>kt the Poyson at his Lip,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> Drank it from his Eyes;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> it in every Vain did creep,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> did my heart Surprize.</l>
                  <pb n="52" facs="tcp:191925:31"/>
                  <l>Sweet was the <hi>Draught</hi> while he was true,</l>
                  <l>Till he his Vows did break;</l>
                  <l>Love from my Breast like Lightning flew,</l>
                  <l>And in my Eyes did speak.</l>
                  <l>The Blushes then did leave my Face,</l>
                  <l>My Wounds encreas'd their smart;</l>
                  <l>My Blood ran swift from ev'ry place,</l>
                  <l>To guard my Fainting heart.</l>
                  <l>Go Perjur'd wretch <hi>be gone</hi> I cry'd,</l>
                  <l>Since you can use me <hi>thus;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That you may ever be deny'd,</l>
                  <l>Shall always be my Curse.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>On <hi>Mellena</hi>'s absenting her<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> a whole day when I was Si<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </head>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>MEllena</hi> can no longer boast,</l>
                  <l>Of constant Love to me;</l>
                  <l>I look upon that Heart as lost,</l>
                  <l>That once can absent be.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="53" facs="tcp:191925:31"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>eart that loves, admits no Stay,</l>
                  <l>But soon will passage get;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>n Locks nor Bolts do keep the way,</l>
                  <l>The Passion can't be great.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>'re made those <hi>Harangues</hi> of Love,</l>
                  <l>Nor sigh'd so much as She;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> yet I find a Softness move,</l>
                  <l>Beyond what hers can be.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> I my Liberty like her,</l>
                  <l>I'de not such distance keep;</l>
                  <l>I no one like her pre<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>er,</l>
                  <l>None wounds my Soul so deep.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>pon a Present of Fruit sent me by an unknown Hand suspecting it came from <hi>Mellena.</hi>
               </head>
               <lg>
                  <l>THe Gift was tart, but kind was the Intent,</l>
                  <l>I'm sure I took it so how e're 'twas meant.</l>
                  <pb n="54" facs="tcp:191925:32"/>
                  <l>The Gift was grateful, and <hi>if Right I Guess,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The Giver needs must find the same success;</l>
                  <l>Tell her I will not of her Present Tast,</l>
                  <l>Till with her Company I first am Blest.</l>
                  <l>Grant me but always that, I ask no more,</l>
                  <l>Nor will I envy Misers with their Store:</l>
                  <l>Nor Crowns nor Scepters, which I deem as <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>When but compar'd to our indulgent Joys.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem__song">
               <head>A <hi>SONG.</hi>
               </head>
               <lg>
                  <l>ASk me no more why I am swell'd with <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>Since daily crowds of strong insulting <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Harangue</hi> my melting Soul,</l>
                  <l>To all the softness of a Love-sick Fo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>That I <hi>Myrtilla</hi> Lov'd I ever knew,</l>
                  <l>But Thought withall <hi>Myrtilla</hi> too was True,</l>
                  <l>For with such art so kind she seem'd▪</l>
                  <l>That I for ever, ever could have Drea<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>For 'twas all Vision that my Sense took in,</l>
                  <l>Charm'd to a Slumber by her Wit and Mein.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <pb n="55" facs="tcp:191925:32"/>
               <head>Ʋpon the Sudden Change of <hi>Capadora</hi>'s Brow. By <hi>I. S.</hi> Esq;</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>ONce I beheld her (Pardon me the Sin</l>
                  <l>Of boldly Contemplating things Divine;)</l>
                  <l>As in a Trance She seems, nor looks nor minds</l>
                  <l>The least Diversion, tho' among her Friends.</l>
                  <l>I watch'd and wonder'd till by by swift surprise,</l>
                  <l>Her Elevated Brow rose o'or her Eyes;</l>
                  <l>This done; She soon return'd (to'r Self and us)</l>
                  <l>Excellent Company —</l>
                  <l>— But why was it thus?</l>
                  <l>Why moves her fair Brow after such a pause?</l>
                  <l>I find this is and only this the Cause.</l>
                  <l>Her serious Soul an Emissary sends,</l>
                  <l>To visit Angels her Celestial Friends;</l>
                  <pb n="56" facs="tcp:191925:33"/>
                  <l>With whom She constant holds intelligence,</l>
                  <l>Sends often thither, and hears oft from the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>Her looks a while are Grave, her Voice is m<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>Her Soul with it's own thoughts b'ing in disp<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>Till on a sudden in its errand taught,</l>
                  <l>Thorow the Window of her Eye is brought,</l>
                  <l>Now Pearching on her Brow a Winged Thought▪</l>
                  <l>Some short Ejaculation sure it is,</l>
                  <l>To stop some Evil or procure some Bliss;</l>
                  <l>Delaying there a while as if, 'twou'd see</l>
                  <l>On her fair Face Heav'n in Epitome:</l>
                  <l>Or else as other Travellers will do,</l>
                  <l>First in the Map, see Countries where they go▪</l>
                  <l>Or if by a Pardonable error took,</l>
                  <l>Heav'n really to be in her dear look;</l>
                  <l>Shrowding into her Brow, as the Best place,</l>
                  <l>Taking her Eye to be the Throne of Grace▪</l>
                  <l>Nor can I blame the Spirit, since Thousands a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>Mistaken in a Way not half so Fair;</l>
                  <l>But by our Company b'ing undeceiv'd,</l>
                  <l>It upward sprung and left her brow new wa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>You may have seen a Bough (where <hi>Philomel</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="57" facs="tcp:191925:33"/>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>er her warbling Musick bids farewel</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>pairing to her Mates) bend to express</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> grateful Complement to her parting Guests,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>v'd by the pressure of her Springing Shanks</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>e yielding Twig pays in that motion thanks.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <hi>Capadora</hi>'s Pray'r to Heav'n aspir'd,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>hile the Misterious motion we admir'd.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem__song">
               <head>A <hi>SONG.</hi>
               </head>
               <lg>
                  <l>FArewel my only Joy, Farewel,</l>
                  <l>How I have Lov'd thee, only I can tell;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>en welcome Death, since <hi>Strephon</hi>'s lost,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>me hast me to th' <hi>Elyzian</hi> Coast.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>nseless and Pale, there lay me down,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ith this Inscription o're my Tomb:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ay, Reader, stay be not afraid,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ere lies the Constant, Constant Virgin Dead.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <pb n="58" facs="tcp:191925:34"/>
               <head>On Intrest.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>NO, no, 'tis Intrest now the World does <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>And Intrest we more than our King Ob<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>What is't for Intrest Men won't Gladly do?</l>
                  <l>Mortgage their Souls and <hi>Glorious</hi> Heav'n forego.</l>
                  <l>Man for his Intrest will his Friend Betray,</l>
                  <l>If once Almighty Intrest leads the Way.</l>
                  <l>Beauty and Wit are now esteem'd no more,</l>
                  <l>In the Fair <hi>Sex</hi> without the Golden Ore;</l>
                  <l>But be she once Possest with Bags of Gold,</l>
                  <l>No matter whether She's Ugly or Old;</l>
                  <l>A Whore, or Baud, or a Chimny-Sweepers Daug<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>There's ne're a Beau in Town but ventures at he<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>Poor Muckworm, Animals bred by the <hi>Sun,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Go and Adore the <hi>Dunghil</hi> whence you <hi>Sprung:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Go see if there you find true Happiness,</l>
                  <l>Or hope hereafter for Eternal Bliss.</l>
                  <pb n="59" facs="tcp:191925:34"/>
                  <l>While my Sublimer Thoughts to Heav'n I raise,</l>
                  <l>And will for what I'njoy my Maker praise;</l>
                  <l>Content and Easie with my little Store,</l>
                  <l>Secure of that, ne're wishing to have more.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>On Happiness.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>NO, 'tis Illusion all, there ne're was yet,</l>
                  <l>True Happiness on this Dull Earth,</l>
                  <l>We think it is compriz'd in Wit,</l>
                  <l>But that first gives our Sorrows Birth.</l>
                  <l>For we might much more Happier be,</l>
                  <l>Cou'd we no Distinction make;</l>
                  <l>Did not these Mortal Eyes once see:</l>
                  <l>What difference 'twixt Sleep and Wake.</l>
                  <l>The Eye our Reason does mislead,</l>
                  <l>In fixing it on things Below;</l>
                  <l>Our Reason follows but its Guide,</l>
                  <l>Which left, it might Immortal Grow.</l>
                  <l>Turn then thy wandring Balls to Heav'n,</l>
                  <l>'Tis there from whence true Joys do Flow,</l>
                  <pb n="60" facs="tcp:191925:35"/>
                  <l>Let from this World thy thoughts be Driv'n,</l>
                  <l>If thou true Happiness wilt know.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>On my Fate.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>WEll! since 'tis so, so let it ever be,</l>
                  <l>I hate the World as much as that does <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>A Sawsy, Proud, Insulting World,</l>
                  <l>Let it be to Confusion hurl'd;</l>
                  <l>'Twill be but what it was, a Sorded thing,</l>
                  <l>Till thrown in order by our Heav'nly King.</l>
                  <l>What can there be to make me Covet it?</l>
                  <l>Not Wealth, nor Beauty, but Sublimer Wit.</l>
                  <l>Grant me that Wish and I will envy none,</l>
                  <l>No not the greatest Monarch on his Thorne.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <pb n="61" facs="tcp:191925:35"/>
               <head>On a Gentleman taking a Pocket-Glass from <hi>Lucinda,</hi> sent it back with this Following Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pology.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>I Purpos'd, Madam, for my part,</l>
                  <l>To take your Glass and leave my Heart;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ut least you think th' Exchange too Small,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>'ve left your Glass my Heart and all.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>f of my Service you'll allow,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>'le come to Church, but pray to you;</l>
                  <l>And thank with all the kinder Powers,</l>
                  <l>That made me Passionately yours.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <pb n="62" facs="tcp:191925:36"/>
               <head>The Penitent.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>GReat God! when Sullen darkness Crowns th' Ai<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>With Horror, then O let me not Despair</l>
                  <l>Of thy dear Presence, but for ever be</l>
                  <l>A Shield between my dismal Faults and me,</l>
                  <l>Faults did I say, nay Crimes of Blackest dy,</l>
                  <l>Crimes for which I in Justice ought to Die.</l>
                  <l>And when my Temples shadow'd are with Sleep,</l>
                  <l>Let Angels my unguarded Genious keep:</l>
                  <l>And watch my Thoughtless and depraved Will,</l>
                  <l>From present Dangers, and from future Ill.</l>
                  <l>This grant Eternal Being and my days</l>
                  <l>I'le spend in Singing thy Eternal Praise.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>Lifes Happiness.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>HE that can leave the solid Joys of Life,</l>
                  <l>The charming Blessings of a Virtuous Wife▪</l>
                  <pb n="63" facs="tcp:191925:36"/>
                  <l>Whose chearful Brow and soft Endearments give,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>h Bliss, as none but happy Men Receive:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>hose kind Discretion stems the Tide of Love,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>d makes it with more lasting Pleasure move,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>hose Hony-Moon ever at Full remains,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>at don't begin with Horns nor end in Wanes;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>hose mutual Hearts such Halcion Minutes bring,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> make their Lives gay as the Infant Spring;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ch Souls are calm, Love sweetens all their cares,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>d Crowns their Life, and Conquers all their fears.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>e that in one may find such Charms, and yet</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>r want of Fortune his Lov'd Mistress quit,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> does from Fate her utmost Rage deserve,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ho will to please his Pride his Pleasure starve.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ant me, ye Gods, such solid Joys to prove!</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> Desart's Heaven with the Nymph I Love:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ent to walk within our safe retreat,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> Aged Oak shou'd be my Mansion seat;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>hose lofty <hi>Structure</hi> Heaven alone can raise,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>d stands a lasting Monument of Praise;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> Name more Ancient Pedigree does know;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>r better Arms, no Heraldry can show:</l>
                  <pb n="64" facs="tcp:191925:37"/>
                  <l>Under whose reverend Branches I should be,</l>
                  <l>More happy in the Converse of my She,</l>
                  <l>Than Heir Apparent of the Family.</l>
                  <l>From thence derive my Happiness and Fame,</l>
                  <l>Contents th' additional Title to my Name:</l>
                  <l>Let the Ambitious toil away their Prime,</l>
                  <l>And purchase Riches with their Loss of Time;</l>
                  <l>Let them Drudge on, fatigue their Life away,</l>
                  <l>Look Old with Care, and in their Youth Decay▪</l>
                  <l>While I in lower Station live and move,</l>
                  <l>Enough's sufficient, where the Want's not Love.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem__song">
               <head>A <hi>SONG.</hi>
               </head>
               <lg>
                  <l>IT is a Sin for Maids to Love,</l>
                  <l>At least to tell their Flame;</l>
                  <l>Tho' mine an Angry God wou'd move,</l>
                  <l>And make a Tyrant tame.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Yet I've that Pride within my Breast,</l>
                  <l>That will my Love conceal;</l>
                  <pb n="65" facs="tcp:191925:37"/>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ho' twere to gain an Age of rest,</l>
                  <l>One thought would not reveal.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>et he I Love is gay and young,</l>
                  <l>Has all the Charms of Youth;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>nd I'd consent to be undone,</l>
                  <l>Had he but Love and Truth.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> still in secrecy love on,</l>
                  <l>And hug my pleasing Chain;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ince such a Charmer put it on,</l>
                  <l>Tho't gives perpetual pain.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>The Vow-Breaker.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>THere's nought on Earth so false can be,</l>
                  <l>As that Ungrateful, wretched he,</l>
                  <l>That first did break his Faith with me.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>He must be Damn'd of consequence,</l>
                  <l>Since he still heightens his offence,</l>
                  <l>With Crimes of feigned Innocence.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="66" facs="tcp:191925:38"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>By all that's Sacred, just or true,</l>
                  <l>Each day did he with Oaths pursue</l>
                  <l>His Love, and Vow'd it constant too.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>Ʋpon Inconstancy.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>IT is but just, a Constant heart</l>
                  <l>Shou'd for its Vertue <hi>Suffer;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Or Martyrdom must be the Part,</l>
                  <l>Of ev'ry Faithful <hi>Lover.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>A Passion so refin'd as Love,</l>
                  <l>Is purify'd by <hi>Flame;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And 'tis the surest way to prove,</l>
                  <l>A Love the most <hi>Sublime.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This makes our Sex so <hi>Generally,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>By Art Mankind to try;</l>
                  <l>To find a Lover that may be</l>
                  <l>Said for their sakes to die.</l>
                  <l>Indeed of old it was the Fate,</l>
                  <l>Of some to die for Love;</l>
                  <pb n="67" facs="tcp:191925:38"/>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> from their Customs <hi>derogate,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> nothing old approve.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> think Inconstancy no Crime,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> 'tis a Vice in Fashion;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> Perjury is in our time,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> Crying Sin o'th' Nation.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>An Elevated Thought.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>O Say my Soul, for sure I long to know,</l>
                  <l>When thou shalt to those glorious Mansions go;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>e Mansions where all Tears are wip'd away,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> Night is turn'd to Everlasting day:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> such a Day, as which no Mortal can,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>eive the Glory there reveal'd to Man;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> all the borrow'd Joys of fancy'd bliss,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> in the Least describe what Heaven is.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ar e're heard or Tongue did e're impart,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> ye e're saw, <hi>or entred in the Heart,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> splendour of the Beatifick face</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ng refulgence on th' Angellick race.</l>
                  <pb n="68" facs="tcp:191925:39"/>
                  <l>O when will come that ever Glorious day?</l>
                  <l>When Heav'nly Sounds shall to my Ears co<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>Come thou blest Spir't to thy Divine abode,</l>
                  <l>And Reign for ever with thy King and God▪</l>
                  <l>Then shall I shake off dull Mortallity,</l>
                  <l>And keep an everlasting Jubilee.</l>
                  <l>All Earthly Joys I shall at distance view,</l>
                  <l>Those painted Nothings which we all pursue▪</l>
                  <l>Foolish as false, uncertain as they're few.</l>
                  <l>Contemn these gaudy mischiefs, O my Soul,</l>
                  <l>And let them not thy Noblest part <hi>Contro<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That when thou'rt clear of all this Earthly <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>May'st mount above thy Maker to behold.</l>
                  <l>But stay Desires, fly not away so fast,</l>
                  <l>For you have Crimes that will retard your <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>Seek first for Mercy at th' Almighty's Thro<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>There let thy Pray'r and Penitence attone▪</l>
                  <l>For what else thou for ever must bemoan.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <pb n="69" facs="tcp:191925:39"/>
               <head>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>on Mrs. <hi>H—</hi> who bad me Write something of Her.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>FOrgive me, Madam, if my Pen express</l>
                  <l>No other <hi>Rhetorick</hi> than gratefulness;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> mighty Flights are to your Merit due,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> might I choose a Theme it shou'd be you:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> lest I injure in a Stile too low,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> only silent admiration show,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> with th' astonish'd Crowd at distance bow.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> mine's a poor, weak, blushing, Virgin Pen,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>t knows not <hi>Ovid, Cicero</hi> or <hi>Ben,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> whether there be Muses Nine or Ten;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> it knows nothing more than your Command,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> pay its thanks when last it kiss'd your hand.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <pb n="70" facs="tcp:191925:40"/>
               <head>The Resignation.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>AH! my too rigorous Stars, why do <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>Impose such Contradictions on my W<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>Why did you place me in this little Sphere</l>
                  <l>To tread th' uneasie round with so much care▪</l>
                  <l>Continual Slave to watchfulness and fear.</l>
                  <l>Condemn'd to Nonsence, Pride, Impertinence▪</l>
                  <l>Each day contemn'd by those of lesser Sence,</l>
                  <l>And serve as <hi>Engine</hi> to their Arrogance.</l>
                  <l>Oh! 'tis a little, saucy, Noisy World,</l>
                  <l>That has the calmness of my Soul <hi>unfurl'd;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But why shou'd I in restless Passion burn?</l>
                  <l>For what will all to <hi>Dissolution</hi> turn.</l>
                  <l>Then each proud Animal that treads the Ea<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>That pond'rous Mass of dirt from which they'd <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>And the Proud flesh of nicer Mortal must</l>
                  <l>Moulder to Earth and mix with common dust▪</l>
                  <l>Then who's the Mighty man of Wealth or W<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>Which held the Plo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>, or which the Burnish'd <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="71" facs="tcp:191925:40"/>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>en there will need no Herald to decide,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ich Blood was best, Father or Mothers side,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> if to Prince or Beggar near Alli'd.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>hat great Day 'twill not be understood,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ho this Man was, but whether Just and Good;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>en let me not with Heav'n expostulate,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>r wonder at the Just decrees of Fate:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>s th' Almighty's Will it should be so,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>hose Breath can make the <hi>Alpian</hi> Mountains bow.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>en cease Tempestuous Thoughts, be calm and still,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>ates the Word,</hi> 'tis the Almighty's Will;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ith all submission I, great God, resign,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> thou my Guide, for I am only thine.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem__song">
               <head>A <hi>SONG.</hi>
               </head>
               <lg>
                  <l>YEs there are wonders in his Face,</l>
                  <l>But in his Conversation more;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ch accent carries such a Grace,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> spoke by an Almighty Pow'r.</l>
                  <pb n="72" facs="tcp:191925:41"/>
                  <l>When e're he does his Passion move,</l>
                  <l>In awful Thunder 'tis exprest;</l>
                  <l>But oh! no Laurel shelters Love,</l>
                  <l>Or Guards a too too willing Breast.</l>
                  <l>But if I e're deceiv'd must be,</l>
                  <l>As soon or late all Virgins are;</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Strephon's</hi> the dear, deceitful he,</l>
                  <l>For whom (alas) I wou'd despair.</l>
                  <l>The grand <hi>Fatigue</hi> of Faithless Love,</l>
                  <l>I should a Pleasure call;</l>
                  <l>None can my Passion disapprove,</l>
                  <l>When I to Sence a Victim fall.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>The Rebel.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>MUtinous Heart! why dost thou so molest▪</l>
                  <l>My all serene and ever Peaceful Breast▪</l>
                  <l>Abroad I've kept thee safe from Batteries,</l>
                  <l>At home secur'd thee from all Enemies;</l>
                  <l>Guarded thee from the never failing Tongue,</l>
                  <l>(Artillery so Fatal to the Young)</l>
                  <l>That thou my Heart hast yet escap'd the Wrong.</l>
                  <pb n="73" facs="tcp:191925:41"/>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>o Tears, nor Oaths, nor Vows did ever move,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>y yet Unconquer'd <hi>mighty self</hi> to Love.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>d what tho' you no Conquest e're did gain?</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>r <hi>Valour</hi> you with Glory may maintain;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> Laurels yet did never Grace your Brow,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>illows no Tribute to your Temples owe.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>hy will you then, Ungrateful as you are,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>aise in your own Dominions civil War?</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> you have your dear Country thus Betray'd,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ou must expect that Strangers will Invade;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ay I my self, the Empire will resign,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>o some kind Heart now while the Pow'r is mine:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ather than bear unnat'ral Tyranny,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>nd by thy Barb'rous beating poorly Die,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> will Submit to any Monarchy.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ou may go wander where you will for me,</l>
                  <l>Take up with any little Fighting he,</l>
                  <l>Or go a Volunteer' gainst th' Enemy.</l>
                  <l>You may be Welcome in a Fight at Sea,</l>
                  <l>The Navy has more Rebels there than thee;</l>
                  <l>You may like them do well in such a Cause,</l>
                  <l>Who break their own, scarce keep anothers Laws.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem__acrostic">
               <pb n="74" facs="tcp:191925:42"/>
               <head>An Acrostick on Sir <hi>J. H.</hi>
               </head>
               <lg>
                  <l>JUstice and Love, those attributes Divine,</l>
                  <l>On you descend from the <hi>Jessian</hi> Line;</l>
                  <l>Since that blest Race, our Records have not kn<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>Each single Grace so much abound in one:</l>
                  <l>Prophets of old were but the Counter-part,</l>
                  <l>Here's yet Another after Gods own heart.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Humble and Great are wonders when they joyn,</l>
                  <l>Each centers here to make your stamp Divine;</l>
                  <l>Reward him Heav'ns with your peculiar Grace,</l>
                  <l>Number him Chief amongst thy Chosen Race,</l>
                  <l>Eternally to view thy Beatisick Face.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem__song">
               <head>A <hi>SONG.</hi>
               </head>
               <lg>
                  <l>WHy is not Wit with Beauty joyn'd?</l>
                  <l>I hate a Face without a Mind;</l>
                  <pb n="75" facs="tcp:191925:42"/>
                  <l>If e're I to the Sex submit,</l>
                  <l>'Twill be to <hi>Cloes</hi> powerful Wit.</l>
                  <l>For <hi>Celia</hi> tho' divinely Fair,</l>
                  <l>Art may improve, or Age impair:</l>
                  <l>'Tis Wit alone my Passion moves,</l>
                  <l>The only thing that time Improves;</l>
                  <l>The God with Wit must Tip his Dart,</l>
                  <l>And pierce my Ear to wound my Heart.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>To Clemander.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>WHy should <hi>Clemander</hi> tax my Breast,</l>
                  <l>With so much Cruelty?</l>
                  <l>Who ne're did yet <hi>Disturb</hi> your rest,</l>
                  <l>By ways of <hi>Subtilty.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But since unhurt you do complain,</l>
                  <l>True Woman I will prove;</l>
                  <l>And for your mocking Lovers pain,</l>
                  <l>I'le try to win your Love.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="76" facs="tcp:191925:43"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>And if within my Snare you get,</l>
                  <l>As <hi>Maids</hi> such mischiefs do;</l>
                  <l>Know then, <hi>Clemander,</hi> all your Wit,</l>
                  <l>Will not untangle you.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Love is a strange <hi>Pathetick</hi> Power,</l>
                  <l>All Soon or Late endure;</l>
                  <l>And gives a Wound in one short Hour,</l>
                  <l>Which Ages cannot cure.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Therefore take heed to guard your Heart,</l>
                  <l>When e're you Jest with Love;</l>
                  <l>That may in earnest give a Dart,</l>
                  <l>Too <hi>Fatal</hi> to remove.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But if I were the happy She,</l>
                  <l>Could such a Conquest gain;</l>
                  <l>Believe, <hi>Clemander,</hi> I should be</l>
                  <l>Proud always to remain</l>
               </lg>
               <closer>
                  <signed>Yours.</signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <pb n="77" facs="tcp:191925:43"/>
               <head>The Truth.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>I Hate Mankind and all th'accursed crew,</l>
                  <l>That Innocent and harmless Maids undo;</l>
                  <l>Their false dissembling Tongues no Woman can</l>
                  <l>Hear and believe, but surely they're undone.</l>
                  <l>They dress up Love with damn'd Insinuation,</l>
                  <l>The Modish Garb t'undo the whole Creation;</l>
                  <l>They first begin with Madam, I'm your Slave,</l>
                  <l>And must be so, since First the Wound you gave,</l>
                  <l>By Heav'ns those Charming Eyes, and You alone</l>
                  <l>Will claim by due, Mankind to be Your own;</l>
                  <l>Gods! what a Lovely Brow and Front is there</l>
                  <l>To look all Dead! Because you will and dare,</l>
                  <l>An Air so Charming and a Mein Divine,</l>
                  <l>Where Gods and Graces by consent combine;</l>
                  <l>To form a Soul adorn'd with Parts, shou'd be</l>
                  <l>By all that's Noble Lov'd by Sympathy:</l>
                  <l>And since you're thus, consider; 'twill be kind</l>
                  <l>To think I Love as Honour has design'd.</l>
                  <pb n="78" facs="tcp:191925:44"/>
                  <l>These are the large Professions that they make</l>
                  <l>Till gaining hopes the <hi>Thesis</hi> they forsake,</l>
                  <l>The Honour's gone, and Intrest lies at stake.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem__song">
               <head>A <hi>SONG.</hi>
               </head>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>DAmon,</hi> in yonder Shady Grove,</l>
                  <l>Lies that supposed Deity,</l>
                  <l>We Shepherds stile the God of Love,</l>
                  <l>And oft do feel, tho' never see.</l>
                  <l>Alas we do Mistake his Power,</l>
                  <l>Th' Immortal Tit is now no more.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Jove</hi> Angry at his Idle Reign,</l>
                  <l>Undeify'd the Boy;</l>
                  <l>Nor will he let him have again,</l>
                  <l>The Pleasure to Destroy.</l>
                  <l>So all the World may Live at ease,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Lucinda</hi> too do what she Please.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <pb n="79" facs="tcp:191925:44"/>
               <head>On Mrs <hi>D. C.</hi>
               </head>
               <lg>
                  <l>Ardon me, Madam, that I am inclin'd</l>
                  <l>To trace the Matchles Vertue of your Mind;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> I by so Divine a Precedent,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> run my self the Glorious way you went.</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>der</hi> to so great an Enterprize,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> thoughts strait Mounted to the yeilding Skies;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>s in that Sphere, I did your Heart discern</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>lly devoted to <hi>the Great Concern.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> well <hi>Garnish'd</hi> Temple seem'd to me,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>or the ever Living Deity.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> could th'attonement of my Heart suffice,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> my past Crimes, I'd offer'd Sacrafice;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> with Amazement, as I nearer came</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> it burn with such Seraphick Flame;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> I on Sight grew Warm with such Bright Zeal,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> this hour the kindling Influence feel,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>mend each day by your Example still.</l>
                  <pb n="80" facs="tcp:191925:45"/>
                  <l>Pleas'd with such Visions I my Thoughts <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>Till I began your better Part to View,</l>
                  <l>I mean your Godlike Souls more Brighter Po<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>But lost my own by Contemplating You<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>And when retreiv'd, resolv'd t' attempt no <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>Such curious search, I gave the Progress o'<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>Content to Imitate you and Adore.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>The Choice.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>SUre 'tis some mighty Ill that I have <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>To draw this too too fatal suffering▪</l>
                  <l>For I at First was never Born design'd</l>
                  <l>To Study, watch, or please anothers Mind:</l>
                  <l>My humour is unfit for such a task,</l>
                  <l>Who never Truth with Flattery cou'd Mas<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>I ne're cou'd Fawn Inveigle, Swear or Lie</l>
                  <l>Those little arts in Friendship all defie,</l>
                  <l>Whose Souls e're <hi>glow'd</hi> with Generosity;</l>
                  <l>And mine did ever scorn that Sordid end,</l>
                  <l>That does <hi>Intitle</hi> Interest with a Friend.</l>
                  <pb n="81" facs="tcp:191925:45"/>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ell then! Since Honest Truth cannot prevail,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>nd soft complyance not at all avail;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>hat if I (<hi>Stoick</hi> like) sit calmly down,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>onqu'ring my Passions even to a Frown?</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> that perhaps I might the more Offend,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>nd raise the Fury which I wou'd <hi>Suspend;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>or nothing more offends the Passionate,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>han careless Silence when they wou'd <hi>Debate.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> take me hence if this be Living here;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ave to Contention, Discontent and Fear;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>r send me to some Lonely Rural Seat,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ar from the Noise of the Contentious Great;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>here let me live with some Dear Charming She,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>rom Business, Pride, or Affectation free,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> Loving her, She only Loving me.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem__song">
               <head>A <hi>SONG.</hi>
               </head>
               <lg>
                  <l>OFt has he Swore, and I as oft believ'd</l>
                  <l>For with that Tongue the World might be deceiv'd;</l>
                  <pb n="80" facs="tcp:191925:46"/>
                  <gap reason="duplicate" resp="#oxf" extent="1 page">
                     <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb n="81" facs="tcp:191925:46"/>
                  <gap reason="duplicate" resp="#oxf" extent="1 page">
                     <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb n="82" facs="tcp:191925:47"/>
                  <l>But now too plainly I the cheat descry,</l>
                  <l>And will our Sexes cunning use;</l>
                  <l>Next Minute he pretends to die,</l>
                  <l>That minute I'le the Fop refuse.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>When in feign'd Raptures I <hi>Courtillo</hi> see</l>
                  <l>Burn in that fire which he design'd for me;</l>
                  <l>Revenge not Love augments the Flame</l>
                  <l>With scorn of my too deadly hate,</l>
                  <l>Will make the Mighty Lover tame,</l>
                  <l>When dying won't recal his Fate.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then die ingrate <hi>Courtillo</hi> if you please,</l>
                  <l>And when the Pangs of Death do seize;</l>
                  <l>Remember how your <hi>sly Deceit</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Has rackt the poor <hi>Lucinda</hi>'s Breast,</l>
                  <l>Think Heaven will repay the Cheat,</l>
                  <l>And never give the Perjur'd rest.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem__acrostic">
               <pb n="83" facs="tcp:191925:47"/>
               <head>AN ACCROSTICK ON <hi>E. I.</hi> Esq.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>EMbellishment adds nothing to that Name,</l>
                  <l>Distinction sets above the Reach of Fame:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ilst brighter Nature circles o're your brow,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> is an useless Shine that Light to show;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>h Vertue reigns in each accomplish'd part,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ells in your Breast and Triumphs in your Heart.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>pire me (Muse) with something Just to say,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>b not his Honour by your dull delay;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>d round his Temples Lawrels, Myrtle, Bayes,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ild to his wondrous Merit mighty praise.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <pb n="84" facs="tcp:191925:48"/>
               <head>To a Young Lady just befor<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Her Marriage.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>FAir Lovely Maid, permit my Muse to Sha<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>And in your Mighty Joys a Part to bear;</l>
                  <l>She must be more than Pleas'd if you are so,</l>
                  <l>But ah! the wondrous Blessings you bestow,</l>
                  <l>He who Possesses you can only know.</l>
                  <l>The Envied happy He of all Mankind,</l>
                  <l>To whom Heaven has the Fairest Nimph assign<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>With all her brighter Treasury of Mind.</l>
                  <l>Go, and be happy, as your Loves can make,</l>
                  <l>And if he give such Blessings as he take,</l>
                  <l>You must have Joys too great for humane Sense</l>
                  <l>And Immortality on Earth Commence;</l>
                  <l>If Divine pleasure we below would prove,</l>
                  <l>It must be in Sincere and Mutual Love.</l>
                  <l>Where Love rides Admiral Tempests never ri<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>His Days are Halcion, all Serene his Skys;</l>
                  <pb n="85" facs="tcp:191925:48"/>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ch may you find, and such for ever keep,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ill calm your Passage o're the Stormy Deep;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>hes of Joy to you are Needless here</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>o possess more than what a Wish can bear.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> may they ever last without Decrease,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>or may your Love but with your Pulses cease.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>To Strephon.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>TIs Pitty Converse such as yours should be,</l>
                  <l>Excluded when the ends Civility</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>endship 'tis true, too often's a Pretence</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> cheat a Poor unwary Innocence;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>it she whose some experience has made wise,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ews well the mighty Fantome in Disguise,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>arks all her paths which do to Honour lead,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>nd knows the Borrow'd <hi>Juno</hi> e're she's Fled;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ith these discerning Eyes I find in you,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>he real Honour, from the seeming true;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>nd only Grieve I cannot pay in kind</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>hat Generous Civility I find.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <pb n="86" facs="tcp:191925:49"/>
               <head>Some Words sent me by an Ʋnknown Hand.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>WOman the Happy pledge of Heavens goo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>Woman the Perfect product of it's Skil<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </l>
                  <l>'Tis Woman all our happy hours employ,</l>
                  <l>Woman the Center of all Earthly Joy.</l>
                  <l>And yet were I, all she is or can,</l>
                  <l>I would not cease to be that Creature Man;</l>
                  <l>Man as I am, so Man I still would rest,</l>
                  <l>I would be Man to be by Woman blest.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>The Wish.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>COuld poor <hi>Lucinda</hi> have her Wish,</l>
                  <l>It should be bounded all in this,</l>
                  <l>Might She in quietude possess</l>
                  <l>A Friend and Book both good and true;</l>
                  <pb n="87" facs="tcp:191925:49"/>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> he would to Crowns prefer her Bliss,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>d bid the Falser Sex adieu.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>Writ in a Lady's Pocket Book.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>TO Speak my Love I want an <hi>Ovid</hi>'s Tongue,</l>
                  <l>And <hi>Cicero</hi>'s Pen would do your Merit wrong,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>o weak alas is Rhetorick to prove,</l>
                  <l>How much you Merit, or how much I Love.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>The Farewel by Mr. <hi>I. W.</hi>
               </head>
               <lg>
                  <l>Now at our Farewel, <hi>Phillis,</hi> (if you will,)</l>
                  <l>Accept the Sorry Song of <hi>Philophill.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>MY <hi>Phillis</hi> now is all my Song:</l>
                  <l>To her my heart, my hand, my tongue</l>
                  <l>Is now Devoted; only She</l>
                  <l>My Mistress, Saint, and Soul must be.</l>
                  <pb n="88" facs="tcp:191925:50"/>
                  <l>Tho' now the Morning makes no stay,</l>
                  <l>But straight unlocks the Door of Day.</l>
                  <l>Before her early Beams appear,</l>
                  <l>To bring us news the Sun is near,</l>
                  <l>My <hi>Phillis</hi> Stands before my Sight;</l>
                  <l>Her Beauties chace away the Night.</l>
                  <l>Her Light the Darkness does controul,</l>
                  <l>Like Lightning shines into my Soul;</l>
                  <l>And tho' no heat the Sheath do feel,</l>
                  <l>It burns within, and melts the Steel.</l>
                  <l>When forth I walk in Flowery Feilds,</l>
                  <l>The chief delight my <hi>Phillis</hi> yields.</l>
                  <l>No Cloud obscures the <hi>pleasant</hi> Light:</l>
                  <l>'Tis <hi>Phillis</hi> makes the day so bright;</l>
                  <l>See how the Flow'rs do smile on me,</l>
                  <l>'Tis <hi>Phillis</hi> Beauty then I see.</l>
                  <l>The Fields as fragrant are as fair:</l>
                  <l>'Tis <hi>Phillis</hi> breath perfumes the Air.</l>
                  <l>The Birds with Singing please my Ear:</l>
                  <l>Then <hi>Phillis</hi> Voice methinks I hear.</l>
                  <l>When I'me transported with my bliss,</l>
                  <l>From <hi>Phillis</hi> Lips I Steal a Kiss.</l>
                  <pb n="89" facs="tcp:191925:50"/>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> when the Sun that shines so bright,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>s down, and Envies my delight.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> she unvails, might he but stay,</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> kiss her Beauty all away.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ail forbids his amourous <hi>Shines:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>n at my pleasure he repines.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>'d rob me of them by his fall:</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> I in <hi>Phillis</hi> find them all.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>hese delights I mean to rest:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>onick</hi> Pleasure is the Best.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>ON LUCINDA Going to Church.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>IN vain <hi>Lucinda</hi> much in vain,</l>
                  <l>You would conceal your Love;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>hen ev'ry Look and ev'ry Strain,</l>
                  <l>Does more your Passion prove.</l>
               </lg>
               <pb n="90" facs="tcp:191925:51"/>
               <lg>
                  <l>Can the Dear Needle leave it's <hi>North,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Or Nature quite decay;</l>
                  <l>Or can the Earth leave bringing forth</l>
                  <l>In <hi>April</hi> or in <hi>May.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Then may <hi>Lucinda</hi> cease to show</l>
                  <l>The Passion of her Breast,</l>
                  <l>When by each Blush and by each Smile,</l>
                  <l>Her Love is still exprest.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>I doubt not but the other day</l>
                  <l>You went with zeal to Church,</l>
                  <l>But when the grateful Object came,</l>
                  <l>Devotion's left i'th Lurch.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>How was her trembling Heart perplext?</l>
                  <l>'Twixt Earth and Thoughts above;</l>
                  <l>But let the World say what it will,</l>
                  <l>All Powers must yield to Love.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <pb n="91" facs="tcp:191925:51"/>
               <head>Sent me by a Gentleman.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>GIve me the Eyes give me the Charms</l>
                  <l>That Govern'd are by Art;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>hat can our Beaux subdue in swarms,</l>
                  <l>Tho' Beauty has no part.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>nce each affected glance can move</l>
                  <l>Bright Nature wee'l despise;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>hat need of Merit or of Love</l>
                  <l>To make a Fop your Prize.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>We live in such a wretched Age,</l>
                  <l>What can our Passions move;</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>owards and Boys in feuds engage,</l>
                  <l>And Aukward Fools make Love.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <pb n="92" facs="tcp:191925:52"/>
               <head>The Answer.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>TAke you the Artificial Charms,</l>
                  <l>Bright nature I Admire;</l>
                  <l>You Beaus like Bees may Die in Swarms,</l>
                  <l>When Brimstone Face can Fire.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Take the affected Glance you Love,</l>
                  <l>While Merit 'tis I Prize;</l>
                  <l>Beauty so Low does never move,</l>
                  <l>Unless 'tis to Dispise.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>You wrong the Age in which you Live,</l>
                  <l>Nor can I blame that Fair;</l>
                  <l>That slights the Passion Fools do give,</l>
                  <l>When Men of Sence are near.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem__dialogue">
               <pb n="93" facs="tcp:191925:52"/>
               <head>A DIALOGUE BETWEEN <hi>Cloris and Almeria.</hi>
               </head>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>lor.</speaker>
                  <lg>
                     <l>WHat does the bright <hi>Almeria</hi> wish or Fear,</l>
                     <l>Who does so sad in these <hi>rude</hi> shades appear.</l>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>ir Royal Maid, you who in Courts do shine,</l>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>nd whom the Admiring croud does stile Divine;</l>
                     <l>Why do those Eyes, which have their Thousands Slain,</l>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>f glorious Youths, their Beauty waste in Vain?</l>
                     <l>Why thus in Tears which have such Fire sent,</l>
                     <l>Unless the Gods fresh Danger to prevent,</l>
                     <l>Destroy their Pow'r by Contrary Element.</l>
                  </lg>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>A.</speaker>
                  <lg>
                     <l>Alas you little know within this Shade,</l>
                     <l>Where nothing does your soft repose invade.</l>
                     <l>How we in Courts destroy our Infant hours,</l>
                     <l>With baffled hopes and Loves Almighty Powers.</l>
                     <pb n="94" facs="tcp:191925:53"/>
                     <l>Where Men vile Men with false Pretentions move▪</l>
                     <l>Our Innocent unthinking Hearts to Love.</l>
                     <l>By Vows and Oaths and promised greatness won,</l>
                     <l>By Love and by Ambition we're undone.</l>
                  </lg>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>C.</speaker>
                  <lg>
                     <l>'Tis true our Village harbours no Deceit,</l>
                     <l>Whose Pride is to be Honest more then Great:</l>
                     <l>In Constancy our Emulation lies,</l>
                     <l>And Words alone are obligatory Tyes.</l>
                     <l>No Shepherds here call back that Faith they've giv<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </l>
                     <l>Their Vows are Sacred both to us and Heaven,</l>
                     <l>But speak <hi>Almeria,</hi> your sad tale impart,</l>
                     <l>I have a Lovers pity in my Heart.</l>
                     <l>Sit down beneath this Poplar here by me,</l>
                     <l>Love will sometimes be eased by Sympathy.</l>
                  </lg>
               </sp>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>A.</speaker>
                  <lg>
                     <l>Know then when first I trod the Ambitious <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </l>
                     <l>Of <hi>Albions</hi> Court, the Glory of our Isle.</l>
                     <l>From Rural Shades a harmless Maid I came,</l>
                     <l>Untoucht in Thought, and Spotless in my Fame.</l>
                     <l>Unused to Artifice in Face or Mind,</l>
                     <l>Fair without Art, and Innocently kind.</l>
                     <pb n="95" facs="tcp:191925:53"/>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>atch my tender Flock was all my care,</l>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>eaving flowry Garlands for my Hair;</l>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>st every Shepherd strove upon the Green</l>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>se Voice should first Proclaim <hi>Almeria</hi> Queen.</l>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> I unknown to other Joys was pleas'd,</l>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> wild Ambition had my Parents Seiz'd.</l>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> thought my Beauty lost to Country Swains,</l>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>me to Soft to Live on rugged Plains:</l>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> and Untaught they sent me to the Court,</l>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>re all the Youth of Quality resort;</l>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>demn'd to Ceremony, Dress, and <hi>Air,</hi>
                     </l>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> Wig and Stinkirk they Attack the Fair,</l>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> Coach and Equipage they gild the Bait,</l>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> Carry on the <hi>Mischief to be great;</hi>
                     </l>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>re 'twas my early Hopes were soon deceiv'd,</l>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> gladly what I wisht, I soon believ'd.</l>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> Women too too Credulous alas!</l>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>nk what we wish will surely Come to Pass.</l>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>se gay Deluders led me Fairly on,</l>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> Vows and Promises, to be Undone.</l>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> warn'd by me, you who in Courts reside,</l>
                     <l>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>re Sacrifice your Pleasure to your Pride.</l>
                  </lg>
               </sp>
               <pb n="96" facs="tcp:191925:54"/>
               <sp>
                  <speaker>C.</speaker>
                  <lg>
                     <l>Alas I Pitty poor <hi>Almeria</hi>'s Fate,</l>
                     <l>And is it then so Dangerous to be Great.</l>
                     <l>Is there no Laws for the Unfaithful Sex,</l>
                     <l>Must they still Triumph where they most Perplex▪</l>
                     <l>
                        <hi>Chloris</hi> may Bless the humble Life she Loves,</l>
                     <l>She meets no Disapointments in these Groves.</l>
                     <l>If she her Careless Flocks secure from Harm,</l>
                     <l>No other Fear her Chearful brest Alarms,</l>
                     <l>To Fright her from her welcome Shepherds Arm<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </l>
                     <l>Stay here with me, and I will part my Sheep,</l>
                     <l>On yonder Hill you the One half shall keep,</l>
                     <l>On shady Banks wee'le wast the Scorching day,</l>
                     <l>With Songs and Tales wee'le Drive your Grief a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </l>
                  </lg>
               </sp>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>